<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on OMFG</title>
    <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on OMFG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 22:08:46 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole Fretboard</title>
      <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/5-whole-fretboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 22:08:46 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</author>
      <guid>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/5-whole-fretboard/</guid>
      <description>This is the fifth and final lesson on learning the notes of the fretboard::
 Just 12 notes. (Background material) Open and E strings Fret 5 and String 5 Octave Shapes Whole Fretboard (this page)  This diagram of all the natural notes should look considerably less intimidating now:
  The natural notes     We&amp;rsquo;ve already drilled extensively on the outside E strings and the A strings, but we still need to learn the remaining notes on the D, G, and B strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fret 5 &amp; String 5</title>
      <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/3-fret5-string5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 12:32:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</author>
      <guid>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/3-fret5-string5/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get a few more notes under our fingers and into our brains.
This is part 3 of 5:
 Just 12 notes. (Background material) Open and E strings Fret 5 and String 5 (this page) Octave Shapes Whole Fretboard  As we described previously, if we KNOW the notes of the open strings and at the 12th fret, it&amp;rsquo;s handy to also KNOW the notes at the 5th fret because it&amp;rsquo;s almost half way between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open and E Strings</title>
      <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/2-open-and-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 20:01:30 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</author>
      <guid>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/2-open-and-e/</guid>
      <description>This document presents a number of exercises to learn the names of all the natural notes on the fretboard.
This is part 2 of 5:
 Just 12 notes. (Background material) Open and E strings (this page) Fret 5 and String 5 Octave Shapes Whole Fretboard  Try not to be intimidated, but here is what we are eventually going to learn (this diagram is just for the first 15 frets, but you will learn your entire fretboard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just 12 Notes</title>
      <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/1-just-12-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 16:39:18 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</author>
      <guid>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/1-just-12-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 of a 5 page tutorial on how to learn the notes on the fretboard:
 Just 12 notes. (Background material — this page) Open and E strings Fret 5 and String 5 Octave Shapes Whole Fretboard  This section is purely background and doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any exercises.
If you are in a rush and just want to start learning the fretboard, skip this page for now and proceed directly to learning the notes on the open and E strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Operator&#39;s Manual for Guitar</title>
      <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</author>
      <guid>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>This site&amp;rsquo;s conceit is to take an engineer&amp;rsquo;s approach to teaching the instrument. It attempts to be an &amp;ldquo;Operator&amp;rsquo;s Manual&amp;rdquo; for the guitar, written by an engineer for other engineers.
Engineers can&amp;rsquo;t help themselves from asking &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; at every conceivable step of a learning process. Music is such a deep topic that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get lost in the weeds doing this, but the only thing worse to an engineer than not getting an answer is getting a wrong one!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octave Shapes</title>
      <link>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/4-octave-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rw@pobox.com (Rex Walters)</author>
      <guid>https://lessons.doiwalters.com/page/4-octave-shapes/</guid>
      <description>This is part 4 of 5 pages dedicated to learning the notes on the fretboard:
 Just 12 notes. (Background material) Open and E strings Fret 5 and String 5 Octave Shapes (this page) Whole Fretboard  Here&amp;rsquo;s the complete diagram of the fretboard again:
  The natural notes     Hopefully it looks a little less intimidating than the first time you saw it.
Now that you already KNOW a bunch of landmarks, it&amp;rsquo;s time to learn a neat little navigational trick called octave shapes to help you (quickly) find the remaining notes by dead reckoning from those landmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>